<dictionary>
    <word>
        <word-base>confront</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>face up to and deal with (a problem or difficult situation).</definition>
        <example>He confronted his fears by trapping the spider under a bowl.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>rage</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to move, rush, dash, or surge furiously.</definition>
        <word-variant>rages</word-variant>
        <example>The river raged down the slope at a blistering pace.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>amuse</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to cause mirth, laughter, or the like</definition>
        <example>The comedian amused the audience with a steady stream of jokes.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>avert</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to turn away or aside</definition>
        <example>Feeling guilty the lawyer decided to avert his gaze from the judge.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>juxtapose</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to place close together or side by side, especially for comparison or contrast</definition>
        <example>The artist decided to juxtapose his newest creations to compare them.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>solve</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to find the answer or explanation for; clear up;explain</definition>
        <example>The student asked the professor for some help to solve the homework problem</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>insurmountable</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>incapable of being surmounted, passed over, or overcome, insuperable</definition>
        <example>The hiker always thought that Mount Everest was an insurmountable mountain.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>inane</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>lacking sense, significance, or ideas;silly</definition>
        <example>The father was slowly growing tired of all the inane questions his child kept asking him.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>trivial</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>of very little importance or value; insignificant</definition>
        <example>The politician told his aide not to bother him with any more trivial matters.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>traumatic</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>of, relating to , or produced by a trauma or wound</definition>
        <example>The lone soldier didn't want to talk about his traumatic experiences in the war, becuase it pained him too much.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>ineffable</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>incapable of being expressed or described in words; inexpressible</definition>
        <example>After getting into her dream college she was unable to contain her ineffiable joy.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>trudge</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to walk, especially laboriously or wearily</definition>
        <word-variant>trudges</word-variant>
        <example>The rather chubby man while working out decided to trudge up the long flight of steps for more exercise.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>meander</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to proceed by or take a winding or indirect course</definition>
        <word-variant>meanders</word-variant>
        <example>The stream meandered through the valley</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>edge</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to make or force(one's way) gradually by moving sideways</definition>
        <word-variant>edges</word-variant>
        <example>The shopper decided to edge her way through the shopping crowd.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>amble</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to go at a slow, easy pace; stroll;saunter</definition>
        <word-variant>ambles</word-variant>
        <example>He ambled around the town</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>jargon</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>the language, especially the vocabulary peculiar to a particular trade, profession, or group.</definition>
        <example>The scientist decided that he couldn't understand all the medical jargon the doctors were using.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>merit</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>something that deserves or justices a reward or commendation ; a commendable quality, act,etc..</definition>
        <word-variant>merits</word-variant>
        <example>The book's only merit is its sincerity.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>disadvantage</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>absence or deprivation of advantage or equality</definition>
        <word-variant>disadvantages</word-variant>
        <example>With blood all over his face the boxer was at a disadvantage.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>reward</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>something given or received in return or recompensation for service, merit, hardship, etc.</definition>
        <word-variant>rewards</word-variant>
        <example>The king bestowed the reward of knighthood upon his trusted general.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>problem</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>any question or matter involving doubt, uncertainty, or difficulty</definition>
        <word-variant>problems</word-variant>
        <example>The problem of the riots was troubling the president greatly.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>taciturn</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>inclined to silence; reserved in speech; reluctant to join in conversation</definition>
        <example>Everyone didn't like Jack's taciturn nature, because it made it hard to keep up a conversation with him.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>gregarious</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>fond of the company of others; sociable</definition>
        <example>Jacky was a very gregarious person. She kept hosting parties every weekend and invited everyone.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>garrulous</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>excessively talkative in a rambling, roundabout manner, epecially about trivial matters</definition>
        <example>Rachel always thought that Mindy's garruolous talk about her dog was boring.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>equivocal</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>allowing the possibilty of several different meanings, as a word or phrase, especially with intent to deceive or misguide; susceptible of double interpretation; deliberately ambiguous</definition>
        <example>Jack's equivocal answer to the confession made Emily so confused.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>arrogant</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>making claims or pretensions of superior importance or rights ; overbearingly assuming; insolently proud</definition>
        <example>The arrogant public official wouldn't stop claiming how he was the only one fit to lead the people.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>teeming</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>abounding or swarming with something, as with people</definition>
        <word-variant>teeming with</word-variant>
        <example>The house was teeming with hornets.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>devoid</word-base>i
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not possessing , untouched by, void, or destitute</definition>
        <word-variant>devoid of</word-variant>
        <example>Detroit after being filled with people for so many years is now devoid of people.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>destroy</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to reduce(an object) to useless fragments, a useless form , or remains, as by rending, burning, or dissolving;  injure beyond repair or renewal; demolish; ruin; annihilate.</definition>
        <word-variant>destroyed by</word-variant>
        <example>The city Detroit was destroyed by the local gangs residing there.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>improve</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to bring into a more desirable or excellent condition</definition>
        <word-variant>improved by</word-variant>
        <example>The office atmosphere was improved by the flowers.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>active</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>causing activity or change; capable of exerting influence</definition>
        <word-variant>active against</word-variant>
        <example>Unable to withstand the unjust government Jacob decided to commit active treason.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>buttress</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to give encouragement or support to (a person, plan, etc..)</definition>
        <example>Jack decided to buttress the plan about world domination.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>ascertain</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to find out definitely; learn with certainty or assurance ; determine:</definition>
        <example>The judge needed to ascertain the facts before making his judgement</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>dispute</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to engage in argument or debate</definition>
        <example>Johnny decided to dispute with his friend about whether it was pronounced katsup or ketchup.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>refute</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to prove false or erroneous, as an opinion or change</definition>
        <example>Sami began to refute Donald Trump's proposition about creating a wall against Mexico.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>absolve</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to free from guilt or blame or their consequences</definition>
        <example>The court absolved her of guilt in his death</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>temerity</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>reckless boldness; rashness</definition>
        <example>In a fit of temerity Leroy charged into the enemies.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>wisdom</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>quality or state of being wise; knowledge of what is true or right coupled with just judgement as to action; sagacity, discernment, or insight</definition>
        <example> Wisdom is the knowledge that tomato doesn't belong in a fruit salad.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>interest</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>the feeling of a person whose attention , concern, or curiosity is particularly engaged by something</definition>
        <example>She has a great interest in the poetry of Donne.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>trepidation</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>tremulous fear, alarm, or agitation; perturbation</definition>
        <example>Jacky was in a constant state of trepidation after killing her father.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>condescension</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>an act or instance of condescending</definition>
        <example>On succeeding to the throne in September 1824 the dignity of his address and his affable condescension won him a passing popularity.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>atrophied</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>exhibiting or affected with atrophy; wasted; withered; shriveled</definition>
        <example> After starving for a month the begger has an atrophied body.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>contracted</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>drawn together; reduced in compass or size; made smaller ; shrunken</definition>
        <example> The redneck had a rather contracted view about gay marriage.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>elongate</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>extended ; lengthened</definition>
        <word-variant>elongated</word-variant>
        <example> The giraffe had a rather elongated neck</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>invigorate</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to give vigor to; fill with life and energy; energize</definition>
        <word-variant>invigorated</word-variant>
        <example> Giving pikachu the battery invigorated pikachu and let pikachu have an extra attack.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>dwindle</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to become smaller and smaller;shrink ; waste away</definition>
        <word-variant>dwindled</word-variant>
        <example> His vast fortune has dwindled away</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>pariah</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>any person or animal that is generally despised or avoided</definition>
        <example> The ugly duckingling didn't like his peers treating him like a pariah.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>ascetic</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>person who leads an austerely simple life, especially one who abstains from the normal pleasures of life or denies himself or herself material satisfaction</definition>
        <example> Living like an ascetic in the woods the lumberjack was happy.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>tyro</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a beginner in learning anything; novice</definition>
        <example> A tyro at swimming Jacky almost drowned numerous times.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>prodigy</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a person , especially a child or a young person, having extraordinary talent or ability.</definition>
        <example> Since he was a child Kevin was a prodigy at the piano.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>prodigal</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a person who spends, or has spent , his or her money or substance with wasteful extravagance ; spendthrift</definition>
        <example> Everyone knew Paris Hilton was a rather prodigal person.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>belie</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to misrepresent</definition>
        <word-variant>belied</word-variant>
        <example> The newspaper belied the facts.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>confirmed</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>made certain as to truth , accuracy , validity, availability, etc..</definition>
        <example> Confirmed reports of new fighting at the front.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>nullify</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to render or declare legally void or inoperative</definition>
        <word-variant>nullified</word-variant>
        <example> The lawyer wanted to nullify the contract.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>fulfill</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to carry out, or bring to realization, as a prophecy or promise</definition>
        <word-variant>fulfilled</word-variant>
        <example> To fulfill the prophecy Hecules lead his army to win the battle.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>ratify</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to confirm by expressing consent , approval , or formal sanction</definition>
        <word-variant>ratified</word-variant>
        <example> George wanted to ratify a new constitutional ammendment.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>irascible</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>easily provoked to anger; very irritable</definition>
        <example> The irascible old man threw chairs at people who walked on his lawn.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>voluble</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>characterized by a ready and continuous flow of words;fluent;glib;talkative;</definition>
        <example> Mark was a voluble spokesman for the cause.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>subdued</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>quiet; inhibited; repressed; controlled:</definition>
        <example> After the argument he was much more subdued.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>contrite</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>filled with a sense of guilt and the desire for atonement; penitent:</definition>
        <example> Jimmy jones was not an acontrite sinner.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>didactic</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>teaching or intending to teach a moral lesson.</definition>
        <example> The english teacher has made the students read a didactic poem about love.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>conciliatory</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>tending to conciliate</definition>
        <example> Jacky was talking in a rather conciliatory manner.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>prolific</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>producing in large quantities or with great frequencies; highly productive</definition>
        <example> James Patterson was a rather prolific writer.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>iconoclastic</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>attacking or ignoring cherished beliefs and long-held traditions, etc., as being based on error , superstition , or lack of creativity.</definition>
        <example> An iconoclastic architect whose buildings are like monumental sculptures.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>contumacious</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>stubbornly perverse or rebellious; willfully and obstinately disobedient</definition>
        <example> Romeo had a rather contumacious personality being rebellious at any given moment.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>pervasive</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>spread throughout</definition>
        <example>The corruption is so pervasive that it is accepted as the way to do business.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>pique</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a feeling of irritation or resentment, as from a wound to pride or self-esteem</definition>
        <example> After losing his tail the dog was in a pique.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>contrition</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>sincere penitence or remorse</definition>
        <example> After his parents died Batman was in a contrition state.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>goodwill</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>cheerful acquiescence or consent</definition>
        <example> Marky Mark was always in a state of goodwill.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>pedantry</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>the character ,qualities, practices, etc. , of a pedant, especially undue display of learning</definition>
        <example> As a man thirsting for knowledge finding another man who was also a pedantry was exciting.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>prudence</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>caution with regard to practical matters</definition>
        <example> The spy was approaching the base with great prudence</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>lament</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to feel or express sorrow or regret for</definition>
        <word-variant>lamenting</word-variant>
        <example>Charizard was lamenting over the loss of his trainer.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>rejoicing</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>the act of a person who rejoices</definition>
        <example> Charmander had a rejoicing after he won the battle.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>affirm</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>To state or assert positively; maintain as true</definition>
        <word-variant>affirming</word-variant>
        <example> The soldier had to affirm his loyalty to the crown.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>comment</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to make remarks, observations, or criticisms</definition>
        <word-variant>commenting</word-variant>
        <example> He refused to comment on the decision of the court.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>mention</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition> to refer briefly to; name, specify, or speak of;</definition>
        <word-variant>mentioning</word-variant>
        <example> Don't forget to mention her contributions to the project.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>incompatible</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>contrary or opposed in character; discordant</definition>
        <example> The artist realized he was using incompatible colors.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>consanguineous</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>having the same ancestry or descent</definition>
        <example> Mark realize his friend and him were connected by a consanguineous family treeline.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>discernable</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>capable of being discerned; distinguisable</definition>
        <example> After ten minutes the man realize the discernible differences between the twins.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>decipher</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to discover the meaning of(anything obscure or difficult to trace or understand)</definition>
        <word-variant>decipherable</word-variant>
        <example> The archaeologist tried to decipher the hieroglyphics.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>consistent</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>agreeing or accordant;compatible; not self-contradictory</definition>
        <example> The trainer's views and actions are consistent.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>jettison</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to throw off(something) as an obstacle or burden; discard</definition>
        <word-variant>jettisoned</word-variant>
        <example> The captain decided to jettison the lifeboats off the ship.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>capsized</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to turn bottom up;overturn</definition>
        <example> Millhouse capsized the boat.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>salvage</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to save from shipwreck,fire , etc</definition>
        <word-variant>salvaged</word-variant>
        <example> The camper salvaged the remains of his book from the fire.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>augment</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to make larger;enlarge in size, number , strength , or extent ; increase;</definition>
        <word-variant>augmented</word-variant>
        <example> His salary is augmented by a small inheritance.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>enumerate</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to mention separately as if in counting; name one by one;specify, as in a list</definition>
        <word-variant>enumerated</word-variant>
        <example> Let me enumerate the many flaws in your hypothesis</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>preeminent</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>eminent above or before others; superior; surpassing</definition>
        <example> He is preeminent in his profession.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>ignominious</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>marked by or attended with ignominy; discreditable; humiliating</definition>
        <example>The general was forced to take an ignominious retreat.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>obsolete</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>no longer in general use; fallen into disuse</definition>
        <example>The cassette is an obsolete object now.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>anachronistic</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>pertaining to or containing an anachronism</definition>
        <example> The trainer had such an anachronistic view about swords in modern warfare.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>perfidy</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>deliberate breach of faith or trust; faithless;treachery</definition>
        <example> Italy's perfidy will not go unpunished.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>truculent</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>brutally harsh; vitriolic ;scathing</definition>
        <word-variant>truculence</word-variant>
        <example> His truculent criticism of her work made her cry.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>serendipity</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>an aptitude for making desirable discoveries by accident</definition>
        <example>The serendipity of getting the first job she applied for.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>pragmatism</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>character or conduct that emphasizes practicality</definition>
        <example>The pragmatism of the instructor saved the group from dying  in the wild multiple times.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>discernment</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>the faculty of discerning;discrimination;acuteness of judgement and understanding</definition>
        <example> Her ability of discernment let the detective solve many cases.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>interminable</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>monotonously or annoying protracted or continued; unceasing;incessant</definition>
        <example> I can't stand that interminable chatter</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>unintelligible</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not intelligible; not capable of being understood</definition>
        <example> The baby talking was unintelligble.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>inconsequential</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>of little or no importance; insignificant;trivial</definition>
        <example> The opponents arguments were inconsequential to the crime at hand.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>implausible</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not plausible; not having the appearance of truth or credibility</definition>
        <example> The butler's alibi of picking up the mail on Sunday was implausible.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>evanescent</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>vanishing;fading away;fleeting</definition>
        <example> The moon's phases were a slow evanescent of sunlight.</example>
    </word>
     <word>
        <word-base>cache</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a hiding place, especially one in the ground, for ammunition, food, treasures, etc.</definition>
        <example>There was always candy in the cache in the hidden drawer.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>glean</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to gather slowly and laboriously, bit by bit.</definition>
        <word-variant>gleaner</word-variant>
        <example>The farmer needed to glean every last piece of rice.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>transformer</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a person or thing that transforms.</definition>
        <example>Everyone loved the show where the transformer became a robot.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>processor</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a person or thing that processes.</definition>
        <example>The human calculater was a processor.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>producer</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a person who produces.</definition>
        <example>A producer made the new film.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>abiding</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>continuing without change; enduring; steadfast</definition>
        <example>The muslims have an abiding faith.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>perennial</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>lasting for an indefinitely long time; enduring</definition>
        <example>Her perennial beauty will be perserved in pictures.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>persuasive</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>able, fitted, or intended to persuade</definition>
        <example>The lawyer had a very persuasive argument.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>irresistible</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not resistible; incapable of being resisted or withstood</definition>
        <example>Romeo's irresistible love for Juliet killed them.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>unmitigated</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not mitigated; not softened or lessened</definition>
        <example>She experienced unmitigated suffering.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>multifaceted</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>having many aspects or phases</definition>
        <example>The multifaceted problem was becoming too hard to solve.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>imperceptive</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not perceptive; lacking perception.</definition>
        <example>The imperceptive giant left his shoe in the firepit.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>tyrannical</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>unjustly cruel, harsh, or severe; arbitrary or oppressive; despotic</definition>
        <example>The tyrannical ruler liked to skin people alive for looking at him weirdly.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>indecisive</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>characterized by indecision, as persons; irresolute; undecided.</definition>
        <example>Jacky took 20 mintues to order food because she was indecisive.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>xenophobic</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>unreasonably fearful of or hating anyone or anything foreign or strange.</definition>
        <example>John was had a xenophobic fear of everything.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>boorish</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>of or like a boor; unmannered; crude; insensitive.</definition>
        <example>The begger had a boorish attitude when facing the rich.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>obscure</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not clear to the understanding; hard to perceive</definition>
        <example>The unknown jester had obsure motivations.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>intractable</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not easily controlled or directed; not docile or manageable; stubborn; obstinate</definition>
        <example>The old man had an intractable disposition.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>confusing</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>causing or tending to cause confusion</definition>
        <example>The spy gave a confusing attempt at explaining the mission.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>elevated</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>exalted or noble; lofty</definition>
        <example>The young boy had elevated thoughts.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>rigorous</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>characterized by rigor; rigidly severe or harsh, as people, rules, or discipline</definition>
        <example>The Mayans upheld rigorous laws.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>impasse</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition> position or situation from which there is no escape; deadlock.</definition>
        <example>With the rain in the sky both armies stood at a impasse.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>deadlock</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a state in which progress is impossible, as in a dispute, produced by the counteraction of opposing forces; standstill; stalemate:</definition>
        <example>The union and management reached a deadlock over fringe benefits.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>solution</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>the act of solving a proble,, question,etc.</definition>
        <example>The situation is approaching solution.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>end</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a point, line, or limitation that indicates the full extent, degree, etc., of something; limit; bounds:</definition>
        <example>Jack's kindness was without end.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>resolution</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>the act of resolving or determining upon an action, course of action, method, procedure, etc.</definition>
        <example>After coming to a resolution the two armies signed the peace treaty.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>conclusion</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a result, issue, or outcome; settlement or arrangement:</definition>
        <example>The restitution payment was one of the conclusions of the negotiations.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>practical</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>consisting of, involving, or resulting from practice or action:</definition>
        <example>Jumping on the trampoline was a practical solution</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>empirical</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>derived from or guided by experience or experiment.</definition>
        <example>We decided to jump off the cliff based on John's empricial decision.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>philosophical</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>of or relating to philosophy :</definition>
        <example>Bulbasaur enjoyed his philosophical studies.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>arcane</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>known or understood by very few; mysterious; secret; obscure; esoteric:</definition>
        <example>She knew a lot about Sanskrit grammar and other arcane matters.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>superficial</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>shallow; not profound or thorough:</definition>
        <example>J.K Rowling was not asuperficial writer.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>obtuse</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not quick or alert in perception, feeling, or intellect; not sensitive or observant; dull.</definition>
        <example>Hodor had a rather obtuse personality.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>studied</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>marked by or suggestive of conscious effort; not spontaneous or natural; affected:</definition>
        <example>After long deliberation Jack gave his studied approval.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>rococo</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>of, pertaining to, in the manner of, or suggested by rococo architecture, decoration, or music or the general atmosphere and spirit of the rococo:</definition>
        <example>The lady in France had a rather rococo charm to her.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>mannered</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>having distinctive mannerisms; affected:</definition>
        <example>The lady had a mannered walk.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>pronounced</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>strongly marked:</definition>
        <example>The fish dish hass a pronounced fishy taste.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>ingenuous</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>free from reserve, restraint, or dissimulation; candid; sincere.</definition>
        <example>The African tribe dresed in an ingenuous manner.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>understated</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>restrained in design, presentation, etc.; low-key:</definition>
        <example>The understated elegance of the dress did not escape the fasionista gaze.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>ridicule</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to deride; make fun of.</definition>
        <example>The spolied boy like to ridicule the beggers on the street.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>lampoon</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to mock or ridicule in a lampoon:</definition>
        <example>The politician loved to lampoon important leaders in the government.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>disparage</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to bring reproach or discredit upon; lower the estimation of:</definition>
        <word-variant>disparaged</word-variant>
        <example>Your behavior will disparage the whole family.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>laud</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to praise; extol.</definition>
        <example>Homer loved to laud the old heros.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>enlighten</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to give intellectual or spiritual light to; instruct; impart knowledge to:</definition>
        <example>We hope the results of our cancer research will enlighten our colleagues.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>train</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to make proficient by instruction and practice, as in some art, profession, or work:</definition>
        <example>The trainer could not wait to train his Charizard to level 100.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>cursory</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>going rapidly over something, without noticing details; hasty; superficial:</definition>
        <example>The student did a rather cursory glance at his notes before the test.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>perfunctory</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>lacking interest, care, or enthusiasm; indifferent or apathetic:</definition>
        <example>In Jack's lectures he reveals himself to be merely a perfunctory speaker.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>detailed</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>having many details </definition>
        <example>To the physic student's delight the detailed probelm wasn't that hard.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>considered</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>thought about or decided upon with care </definition>
        <example>To expert camper gave a considered opinion about the sleeping bag.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>tangential</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>merely touching; slightly connected</definition>
        <example>The instructor only gave tangential instructions on how to build the fire.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>waive</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to refrain from claiming or insisting on; give up; forgo</definition>
        <word-variant>waived</word-variant>
        <example>The slave ownered waived the human rights of his slaves.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>commuted</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to change (a prison sentence or other penalty) to a less severe one</definition>
        <example>The death sentence of the Texan was commuted to life imprisonment.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>arbitrary</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>subject to individual will or judgment without restriction; contingent solely upon one's discretion</definition>
        <example>The friends made an arbitrary decision about dinner.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>change</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to make the form, nature, content, future course, etc., of (something) different from what it is or from what it would be if left alone: to change one's name; to change one's opinion;</definition>
        <word-variant>changed</word-variant>
        <example>If Hitler had won it could have very well changed the course of history.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>lenient</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>agreeably tolerant; permissive; indulgent:</definition>
        <example>The babysitter tended to be lenient toward the children.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>applied</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>having a practical purpose or use; derived from or involved with actual phenomena</definition>
        <example>The student loved applied mathematics.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>color</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to cause to appear different from the reality</definition>
        <example>The witness decided that it was too dangerous to tell the truth and decided to color his testimony.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>impact</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to have an impact or effect on; influence; alter</definition>
        <example>To become a pro video game player it will impact the rest of your life kid.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>cloud</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to make obscure or indistinct; confuse</definition>
        <example>Don't cloud the issue with unnecessary details.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>trigger</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to initiate or precipitate (a chain of events, scientific reaction, psychological process, etc.)</definition>
        <example>The erosion triggered a mudslide.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>devalue</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to deprive of value; reduce the value of.</definition>
        <example>Mark's grand plan was to devalue the cost of turkey.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>objectify</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to present as an object, especially of sight, touch, or other physical sense; make objective; externalize.</definition>
        <example>Men should not objectify women in any way.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>pertinent</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>pertaining or relating directly and significantly to the matter at hand; relevant</definition>
        <example>Say only the pertinent details soldier.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>germane</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>closely or significantly related; relevant; pertinent</definition>
        <example>Please keep your statements germane to the issue.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>anomalous</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>deviating from or inconsistent with the common order, form, or rule; irregular; abnormal</definition>
        <example>Humans might actually be the anomalous in the universe.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>peripheral</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>pertaining to, situated in, or constituting the periphery</definition>
        <example>There still was some peripheral resistance on the outskirts of the town.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>visible</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>apparent; manifest; obvious</definition>
        <example>We were surrounded with no visible means of support.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>puritanical</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>very strict in moral or religious matters, often excessively so; rigidly austere.</definition>
        <example>My parents were always puritanical in educating us.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>prudish</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>excessively proper or modest in speech, conduct, dress, etc.</definition>
        <example>My parents made us dress ina prudish manner when we went to church.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>covert</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>covered; sheltered.</definition>
        <example>My parents gave us a rather covert education.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>camouflage</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to disguise by means of camouflage:</definition>
        <word-variant>camouflaging</word-variant>
        <example>We wanted to camouflage our town from the foreigners.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>misogynistic</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>reflecting or exhibiting hatred, dislike, mistrust, or mistreatment of women.</definition>
        <example>The rednecks had a rather misogynistic view of women.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>miserly</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>of, like, or befitting a miser; penurious; stingy; niggardly.</definition>
        <example>The old name had a miserly nature can kept hoarding all his cash.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>dispatch</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>prompt or speedy transaction, as of business.</definition>
        <example>With great dispatch the mail was delivered.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>celerity</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>swiftness; speed.</definition>
        <example>With great celerity the wall was built.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>grace</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>elegance or beauty of form, manner, motion, or action</definition>
        <example>We watched her skate with effortless grace across the ice.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>effectiveness</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>adequate to accomplish a purpose; producing the intended or expected result</definition>
        <example>The teacher had effective teaching methods.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>slovenly</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>untidy or unclean in appearance or habits.</definition>
        <word-variant>slovenliness</word-variant>
        <example>Much to the CEO's dismay the janitors did slovenly work.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>carelessness</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not caring or troubling; having no care or concern; unconcerned (usually followed by of, about, or in)</definition>
        <example>The queen was disappointed with the prince's carelessness in speech.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>tentative</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>unsure; uncertain; not definite or positive; hesitant</definition>
        <example>The student gave a tentative smile on his face when asked about his homework.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>flimsy</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>weak; inadequate; not effective or convincing</definition>
        <example>My dog ate my homework is now a flimsy excuse.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>unusual</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not usual, common, or ordinary; uncommon in amount or degree; exceptional</definition>
        <example>In the haunted house there was unusal sounds everywhere.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>hackneyed</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>made commonplace or trite; stale; banal</definition>
        <example>The hackneyed images of his poetry.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>outrageous</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>passing reasonable bounds; intolerable or shocking</definition>
        <example>Paying $100 for a bananna is an outrageous price.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>illuminating</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>informative; enlightening.</definition>
        <example>The new evidence casts a new light on the cast illuminating many other inconsistencies.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>mundane</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>common; ordinary; banal; unimaginative.</definition>
        <example>She was wearing such a mundane dress at the ball.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>petty</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>of little or no importance or consequence</definition>
        <example>She did not want to hear any petty grievances</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>weighty</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>important or momentous</definition>
        <example>The weighty negotiations decided the future of the land.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>erudite</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>characterized by great knowledge; learned or scholarly</definition>
        <example>MIT was well known for its erudite community.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>untoward</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>unfavorable or unfortunate</definition>
        <example>Untoward circumstances forced him into bankruptcy.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>extraneous</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not pertinent; irrelevant</definition>
        <example>Anything extraneous to the case throw it away.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>related</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>associated; connected.</definition>
        <example>Anything related to the case give it to the judge.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>catering</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to provide or supply what amuses, is desired, or gives pleasure, comfort, etc.</definition>
        <example>The clown did not want to cater to popular demand.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>similar</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>having a likeness or resemblance, especially in a general way</definition>
        <example>The twins realized that they looked too similar.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>helpful</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>giving or rendering aid or assistance; of service</definition>
        <example>The comments about the raid were very helpful.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>lugubrious</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>mournful, dismal, or gloomy, especially in an affected, exaggerated, or unrelieved manner</definition>
        <example>Ballads were always lugubrious songs.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>melancholy</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>affected with, characterized by, or showing melancholy; mournful; depressed</definition>
        <example>With no parents Batman was always in a melancholy mood.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>jaunty</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>easy and sprightly in manner or bearing</definition>
        <example>The joker was happy and walked with a jaunty step.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>jocose</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>given to or characterized by joking; jesting; humorous; playful</definition>
        <example>The jester had a jocose and amusing personality.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>frivolous</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>characterized by lack of seriousness or sense</definition>
        <example>The jester almost died because of his frivolous conduct.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>ironic</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>using words to convey a meaning that is the opposite of its literal meaning; containing or exemplifying irony </definition>
        <example>The DMZ ironically means demilitarized zone.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>ambivalent</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>having mixed feelings about someone or something; being unable to choose between two (usually opposing) courses of action </definition>
        <example>She is regarded as a morally ambivalent character in the play.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>whimsical</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>given to whimsy or fanciful notions; capricious</definition>
        <example>The fairy was a pixyish, whimsical fairy.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>tardy</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>moving or acting slowly; slow; sluggish.</definition>
        <example>The student was punished because he was tardy.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>authoritarian</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>favoring complete obedience or subjection to authority as opposed to individual freedom</definition>
        <example>Donald Trump's had authoritarian principles.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>strict</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>characterized by or acting in close conformity to requirements or principles</definition>
        <example>When wishing for a wish one must always be strict when saying exactly what they want.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>hidebound</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>narrow and rigid in opinion; inflexible</definition>
        <example>The priest had hidebound beliefs about god.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>perceptive</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>having or showing keenness of insight, understanding, or intuition</definition>
        <example>The detective always gave a a perceptive analysis of the case.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>insightful</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>characterized by or displaying insight; perceptive.</definition>
        <example>The detective always had insightful comments about the case.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>heuristic</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>serving to indicate or point out; stimulating interest as a means of furthering investigation.</definition>
        <example>The heuristic teaching method was slowly working.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>poetic</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>literary criticism treating of the nature and laws of poetry.</definition>
        <example>The english teacher loved to do do studies on poetics.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>prosaic</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>commonplace or dull; matter-of-fact or unimaginative</definition>
        <example>The plebian had a rather prosaic mind.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>repository</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a receptacle or place where things are deposited, stored, or offered for sale</definition>
        <example>The salvation army wants to be a repository of unneeded clothes.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>cache</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a hiding place, especially one in the ground, for ammunition, food, treasures, etc.</definition>
        <example>There was always candy in the cache in the hidden drawer.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>glean</word-base>
        <pos>verb</pos>
        <definition>to gather slowly and laboriously, bit by bit.</definition>
        <word-variant>gleaner</word-variant>
        <example>The farmer needed to glean every last piece of rice.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>transformer</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a person or thing that transforms.</definition>
        <example>Everyone loved the show where the transformer became a robot.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>processor</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a person or thing that processes.</definition>
        <example>The human calculater was a processor.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>producer</word-base>
        <pos>noun</pos>
        <definition>a person who produces.</definition>
        <example>A producer made the new film.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>abiding</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>continuing without change; enduring; steadfast</definition>
        <example>The muslims have an abiding faith.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>perennial</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>lasting for an indefinitely long time; enduring</definition>
        <example>Her perennial beauty will be perserved in pictures.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>persuasive</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>able, fitted, or intended to persuade</definition>
        <example>The lawyer had a very persuasive argument.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>irresistible</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not resistible; incapable of being resisted or withstood</definition>
        <example>Romeo's irresistible love for Juliet killed them.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>unmitigated</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not mitigated; not softened or lessened</definition>
        <example>She experienced unmitigated suffering.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>multifaceted</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>having many aspects or phases</definition>
        <example>The multifaceted problem was becoming too hard to solve.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>imperceptive</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not perceptive; lacking perception.</definition>
        <example>The imperceptive giant left his shoe in the firepit.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>tryannical</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>unjustly cruel, harsh, or severe; arbitrary or oppressive; despotic</definition>
        <example>The tyrannical ruler liked to skin people alive for looking at him weirdly.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>indecisive</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>characterized by indecision, as persons; irresolute; undecided.</definition>
        <example>Jacky took 20 mintues to order food because she was indecisive.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>xenophobic</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>unreasonably fearful of or hating anyone or anything foreign or strange.</definition>
        <example>John was had a xenophobic fear of everything.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>boorish</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>of or like a boor; unmannered; crude; insensitive.</definition>
        <example>The begger had a boorish attitude when facing the rich.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>obscure</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not clear to the understanding; hard to perceive</definition>
        <example>The unknown jester had obsure motivations.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>intractable</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>not easily controlled or directed; not docile or manageable; stubborn; obstinate</definition>
        <example>The old man had an intractable disposition.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>confusing</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>causing or tending to cause confusion</definition>
        <example>The spy gave a confusing attempt at explaining the mission.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>elevated</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>exalted or noble; lofty</definition>
        <example>The young boy had elevated thoughts.</example>
    </word>
    <word>
        <word-base>rigorous</word-base>
        <pos>adjective</pos>
        <definition>characterized by rigor; rigidly severe or harsh, as people, rules, or discipline</definition>
        <example>The Mayans upheld rigorous laws.</example>
    </word>
</dictionary>